( Beverly ) Sure I have .
- Well , I 've discovered why sex is . - You have ? Fantastic !
It 's because humans don 't live underwater .
I don 't get it .
Fish don 't need sex , because they just lay the eggs and fertilise them in the water .
Humans can 't do that because they don 't live in water .
They have to ... internalise the water . Therefore we have sex .
So you mean humans wouldn 't have sex if they lived in the water ?
They 'd have a kind of sex . The kind where you wouldn 't have to touch each other .
I like that idea .
Have you heard of scuba diving ? It 's just new .
Self-contained underwater breathing apparatus .
Exactly .
- Are you thinking what I 'm thinking ? - Yeah . You ask her .
Raffaella , will you have sex with us in our bathtub ? It 's an experiment .
Are you kidding ? Fuck off , you freaks !
I 'm telling my father you talk dirty .
Besides , I know for a fact you don 't even know what " fuck " is !
They 're so different from us , ...
.. and all because we don 't live underwater .
The morculum is working superbly .
- Shall I insert the manticulator ? - Please .
What 's the diagnosis ?
Intra-ovular surgery .
Where did you get that instrument ?
- We had it made for us . - Really ?
Might be fine for a cadaver . It won 't work with a living patient .
( drops instrument )
To our fabulous twins , ...
.. who have , as mere undergraduates , ...
.. already brought us glory .
( all ) Hear , hear !
And here it is , ...
.. in solid gold ...
Er , well , solid gold plate , that is !
( laughter )
The Mantle retractor , which is now the standard of the industry .
Here 's to a brilliant future !
( cheering )
Here it is .
That 's wonderful !
Yeah .
They got the pivot pin in backwards .
Bev , you should 've been there .
I was .
Well ? Are all the necessary parts there , Doc ?
Yes , they are .
And there are a couple of extra ones that shouldn 't be .
Not funny .
Er , no ... I wasn 't joking .
Would you excuse me a minute ? I 'll be right back .
Elly , I want you to look at this woman before you go .
I 'm late , Bev . If I fuck up with the chairman 's wife , we lose our grant .
She 's a trifurcate . I 've never seen anything like it .
Down in a minute . It 's Dr Mantle . Keep the car waiting . Thanks .
Is this Claire Niveau ?
Yeah .
- What , the Claire Niveau ? - Yeah .
Ooh ! What 's she doing here ?
A mini-series . She 's got three agents and a bodyguard in the waiting room .
- And her life is empty without children . - How did you know ?
Bev , everyone knows that ! Don 't you ever read the National Enquirer ?
" Star 's life empty without children . "
I hope it also explained how we can make her fertile , because I don 't think I can .
Then we 'll have to see what I can do .
Elly , what about dinner with the chairman 's wife ?
I guess la bella contessa will have to wait .
Right , let 's take another look .
Yes ...
That 's fantastic .
I 've never had anybody say that about the inside of my body before .
Surely you 've heard of inner beauty ?
I 've often thought there should be beauty contests for the insides of bodies .
You know , best spleen ...
Most perfectly developed kidneys ... Why don 't we have standards of beauty ...
.. for the entire human body , ...
.. inside and out ?
I have a feeling you do .
So I 'll tell ' em to fuck off . Pardon my French .
Don 't tell them to fuck off . I need the work . This mini-series is paying peanuts .
You don 't need to be humiliated .
I 've decided .
I want to be humiliated .
Tell me about my uterus .
( coughs )
Well , it has three doorways .
Three cervixes leading into three separate compartments ...
.. in your uterus . That is fabulously rare .
Do you have trouble with your periods ?
Listen ... um ... I 'm gonna be late for the Axelrod meeting . You 'll be OK ?
Goodbye , Leo . Remember , I need the humiliation as well as the money .
I almost never have periods .
Once or twice a year .
Not very enthusiastic ones .
Could I have triplets , do you think ? One in each compartment ?
No . It doesn 't work like that .
Really ?
How does it work ?
How did it go with la bella contessa ?
Did we get our grant ?
You were great .
Seductive and charming as usual .
And I think you 've got your grant .
Hey , ...
.. wait a minute .
What 's this I hear ? It 's for us , not just for me .
- It 's for Mantle lnc . - Yes , yes .
- I know . - Did she catch on ?
Ah , Contessa , you 're looking so ...
.. l don 't know , so Catherine Deneuve tonight !
And how is Marcello ?
Due cappuccini , per favore , and quickly . The Countess ...
.. is a tigress until she 's got her caffeine in the morning !
Hey , ...
.. l 'm not that bad .
You 're a little bit smoother in real life .
And the movie star , ...
.. how is she ?
She 's expecting me for lunch tomorrow .
So you 're going to find out for yourself .
- Oh , no ! - Oh , yes .
It 's all set up .
The production 's rented her this little apartment ...
.. in Rosedale !
She 'll just be getting out of bed , ...
.. all cosy and warm .
Look , Elly ... the clinic 's booked to the hilt .
We 've got to pay the rent , you know .
- I 'll take your patients . - Oh , yes ( ! )
I want you to go .
Bev , you 've got to try the movie star .
She 's unbelievable .
Don 't worry , you 'll be all right .
Just do me .
( doorbell buzzes )
( door buzzes open )
What did you do to me last night ?
( distant footsteps )
I 'm still vibrating all over .
I learnt it from books .
Mmm , I wish more men would read those books !
Drink ?
No ... thanks .
Well , Doc , ...
.. what 's the prognosis ?
Can I have a baby ... or can 't I ?
You 're asking me that now ? l-l mean , here ?
You said the results would be back today .
There 's no chance that you 'll be able to bear children .
I 'm not surprised .
You must 've been tested before .
Oh , they said ... I wouldn 't have an easy time getting pregnant .
But I 've been taking ...
.. hormone injections .
And I have been extremely promiscuous .
I 've never ...
.. used ... um ... contraceptive devices .
I 've never even thought contraceptive thoughts .
There are other reasons for not sleeping with just ... anybody .
That 's true , you know . I never thought of that .
Oh , of course , you ...
.. had a chance to ...
.. check me out ...
.. thoroughly ...
.. before you jumped on me .
Are you that careful ? Do you only have affairs with patients ?
No , I was ... concerned ...
Am I bad ? ls that it ?
You gonna spank me , Doc ?
It hadn 't occurred to me .
I 've been bad ...
.. and I need to be punished .
I need to be punished .
( sobbing )
Danuta .
( shouts ) Danuta !
As soon as we get some cold water on your face , you 'll feel much better .
Elly ...
- What happened ? - Thank God you 're back , Bev !
I 'm just no good with the serious ones .
Why are you back ?
I 'm just no good with the frivolous ones .
( Elliot laughs ) All she wanted was a little slap on the arse , Bev .
Yeah ?
Yeah , well , I wondered what the fuck my brother had got us into ...
.. behind my back .
She 's an actress , Bev , she 's a flake .
She plays games all the time . You never know who she really is .
Yeah .
I can see that .
You can ?
Yeah !
So ... when are you gonna see her again ? She 's called the clinic five times already .
I don 't know . Perhaps you 'd better go .
Wait a minute , ...
.. this is serious .
- No , it 's not . - Yes , it is !
If we didn 't share women , you 'd still be a virgin .
- No . - You 'd never get laid on your own .
I don 't get out much .
Listen , the beauty of our business is you don 't have to get out ...
- .. to meet beautiful women . - No , I can 't do that . It 's not ...
- Ethical . - No .
It 's not ... safe .
Well , if you don 't go and see her ...
- What ? - I will .
And I 'll tell her I 'm you ...
.. and I 'll do ... terrible things to her .
What sort of terrible things ?
( Claire moans )
( groans )
Oh , God !
Oh , Doctor , ...
.. you 've cured me !
( Claire sobs )
Shh , shh .
What 's the matter , what 's the matter ?
I 'll never get pregnant .
I 'll never have children .
When I 'm dead ... I 'll just be dead .
I 'll ...
.. really never have been a woman at all . Just a girl .
A little girl .
You could always adopt a baby .
It wouldn 't be the same . It wouldn 't be part of my body .
Yes ... that 's true .
Don 't tell . Please don 't tell ...
.. anybody about me . Please don 't tell .
I 'm so vulnerable ... I 'm slashed open .
Who would I tell ? Eh ?
Who would I tell ?
( TV ) And with that seal ofapproval , our 5th bubbly season gets under way .
( door opens )
Hey , hey , hey , ...
.. it 's the swinger !
Yeah ... hi .
So ?
Er , so ...
.. it was nice .
She 's ... a little crazy , but sweet .
Tell me all about it .
Later .
No , now . You might forget something later .
Some yummy detail .
I don 't want to tell you about it .
You don 't what ?
- I want to keep it ... - ( pours drink )
.. for myself .
Listen , ...
.. you haven 't had any experience until I 've had it , too .
You haven 't fucked Claire Niveau until you tell me about it .
Then I haven 't fucked Claire Niveau .
There 's no point to this discussion , Arlene .
There is a point . There definitely is a point !
You started with me and now you won 't carry through .
And ... we have a relationship !
But you test out fine .
It 's your husband that 's the problem , ...
.. and all he probably needs is a good sperm wash .
If it 's only a matter of laundry , why are you opposed to doing it ?
We don 't do husbands .
We do female infertility . We do women . That 's our specialty .
I am a woman ...
.. and I want you to take care of me .
I trust you .
It 's hard enough to find someone ...
.. in the medical profession that you can trust .
Arlene , that 's ... that 's wonderful . I mean , that 's really wonderful , ...
.. but we don 't do husbands .
We don 't deliver babies , either .
We make women fertile , and that 's all we do .
To achieve anything in life , one has to keep life simple .
Don 't you think ?
Irrigation .
It 'd be an exaggeration to say we can make up a new set of fallopian tubes ...
.. using just anything that 's handy .
Those tubes are highly specialised little organs .
But with the kind of help we can offer the process , ...
.. it is possible to ... modify several other organs :
.. the odd vein , ...
.. or , as today , ...
.. we 're using a femoral lymphatic vessel ...
.. to take over the function of conveying the egg ...
.. from the ovary to the uterus .
What are you taking ?
Let me see .
" Dextroamphetamine resin . "
" Dosage form : capsule . "
" 7.5 milligrams . "
" Use : short-term treatment of obesity . "
" Minor side effects : dry mouth , palpitations , ...
.. restlessness , unpleasant taste in mouth . "
" Major ...
.. side effects :
.. sleeplessness , rapid heartbeat , ...
.. euphoria . "
Do you want one ?
Where did you learn all that ?
Doctor , the Physician 's Desk Reference is my favourite bedside reading .
As a matter of fact , ...
.. they tell me that there 's a high incidence of drug use amongst doctors .
- Is that true ? - Yep .
Do you take drugs ?
No .
Well , for pain .
Pain creates character distortion .
It 's simply not necessary .
I 'm often in a lot of pain .
What kind of pain ?
I think ...
.. psychosexual .
I 'd say that was a pretty astute diagnosis .
Though I wouldn 't recommend you using those for that condition .
Who prescribed them for you ?
When you get to be a famous actress ... well , doctors are ...
.. friendly .
Do me a favour . Will you allow me to do the prescribing for you ?
Thanks , Arthur .
You 've forgotten to sign this , Dr Mantle .
Oh .
Sorry .
Actually , my name 's Denis .
Sorry . I always get you confused .
Bye again .
If I had a game of squash now , Terry , I 'd end up a dead man .
I may win , but I 'd be dead at the end of it .
- Tired ? - Yeah , that last one was rough .
- Were you there ? - No , I 'll watch the tape .
I 'll need it to get the FT paper in shape , anyway .
Boston 's yelling at me for it .
Hello , Mary . Then I 'll just need your tissue rejection data .
How 's that coming along ?
Listen , how about I write the paper one time and you collect the data ?
Sure . Just say when . Do you want to see how it 's shaping up ?
No , I trust you to make us look good .
I 'm exhausted .
Too exhausted to see Claire tonight ?
No . Never .
- You 'll need these . - What 's that ?
Butazamine .
She 's heard that it makes sex come on like Nagasaki .
You 're not feeding her pills , are you ?
Listen , baby brother , ...
.. l 've got her number . This lady 's hustling us for drugs .
I don 't think that 's true at all .
- I think we should drop her , Bev . - You drop her !
This is unknown territory we 're moving into .
Just cos we 're handcuffed together doesn 't mean I have to like you !
Handcuffs ?
You don 't get it , do you ?
Listen , honey-mud , ...
.. we 're on the run ... and until we find the release code to this thing ...
.. we 're gonna get to know each other real well .
I suggest we learn to like what we see .
You 're a very self-conscious reader .
Just ... Just loosen up ...
.. and play .
Come on .
Didn 't you ever do routines as a kid ? lmpersonations ?
The only impersonation I ever did was my brother .
I didn 't know you had a brother .
Yeah .
We 're not very close .
Beverly ... That 's a woman 's name .
Why did your mom give you a woman 's name , I wonder ?
It 's not a woman 's name . It 's spelled differently .
It 's still a woman 's name . Does your brother have a woman 's name , too ?
Merian ... spelled with an E ...
.. and an A.
What are you trying to suggest ? That I 'm gay or something ?
My mother wanted girls ?
What the fuck is this bullshit psychoanalysis !
Listen , Doctor , ...
.. l think there 's something wrong with you .
I don 't know what it is , I can 't put a label on it , but ...
.. you 're subtly ...
.. l don 't know ...
.. schizophrenic ...
.. or something .
Sometimes I like you very much ...
.. and sometimes you 're an amusing lay . Not much more .
And I can 't figure out ...
.. why .
( whispers ) Beverly .
One for you .
One for me .
Please come this way .
My dear ...
Sit down , have a drink , ...
.. and tell me everything .
I 'm not sure I know everything .
Start with all this I 've been hearing about you ...
.. and the wonderful Mantle boys .
What are you talking about ?
Claire , this is me - Laura . Please don 't be coy , it 's tedious .
Dear Beverly , ...
.. dear Elliot .
Some claim they can 't tell the difference , ...
.. but not me , dear . It 's obvious to me that ...
Well , before I say anything gauche , tell me which one you 're seeing .
You mean there 's two of them ?
Don 't be an ass , dear . Of course there are two of them .
They 're twins , dear .
Identical twins .
My dear , you 've gone absolutely pale .
Have I said something ?
No , no , not at all . Where 's that waiter ? I want some coffee .
Oh , how sick-making .
I have said something , haven 't I ?
( thunder )
You know , I could get very fond of Butazamine .
Ooooh ... !
Beverly , ...
.. why haven 't you told me that your brother isn 't just a brother ?
Ah , th ... Ah , that .
Yes , that .
It never occurred to me . I mean , he is just a brother .
Um ...
- Is it important ? - Is it important ?
I 've heard you live together in the same apartment .
Yeah , that 's true .
We both like Italian furniture .
God ! Do you sleep in the same bed ?
Oh , Claire , come on !
You come on !
You told me ...
.. you and your brother weren 't close .
And now I find out not only are you identical twins , ...
.. but you live together ...
.. in the same apartment .
What 's he like , ...
.. your twin ?
Well , I mean ... er ...
Of course , h-he looks a lot like me .
Are you identical psychologically ?
Um ...
No , I wouldn 't say that .
When can I meet him ?
You can 't . I mean ...
.. you don 't want to .
( thunder )
But , Beverly ... don 't you understand ?
I have to meet him .
Why ?
I want to know everything about you .
I don 't think it 's a good idea .
You don 't want me to meet your twin . Why is that ?
It 's ... It 's difficult .
It 's very difficult .
That 's it , you see . I want to know why it 's difficult for you .
- My button ... - It 's important to me to know why .
I suppose I ...
.. l could arrange for you and ...
.. Elliot ...
.. to have a drink together .
Uh-uh . Nix .
No good .
Why ?
I want to see you two together .
I know he 's going to have to in the end .
- Ah , there you are . - Here I am .
I 've been really looking forward to this .
Well ... er ...
Claire Niveau , ...
.. this is my brother Elliot .
Hi , Claire ... I hope Bev 's told you what a big fan I am of your movies .
No , he hasn 't . As a matter of fact , he hasn 't mentioned you at all .
Really ? That 's not very flattering .
Well ...
Are you going to sit down ?
Yes , I am .
I feel such a fool , actually . I must be the only woman in town ...
.. who doesn 't know about the fabulous Mantle twins .
What are you drinking ?
Nothing . I want to be very sober right at this moment . I want to be very clear .
There really isn 't any telling you apart , is there ?
Absolutely identical in every respect .
I 'm actually a couple of millimetres taller .
I bet somebody who knew you both - how shall I put it ? -
.. knew you both really well ...
.. could tell the difference .
Without measuring your height , I mean .
What do you mean ?
Beverly 's the sweet one , and you 're the shit . Am I right ?
This is some feisty lady you 've found , Beverly !
Elliot , let 's ease up on the bullshit for a moment . You can be honest with me .
After all , I am laying both of you , aren 't I ?
Er , now , hang on a ...
It 's a sweet little act you have .
You soften them up with all that smarmy concern ...
.. and along comes Dracula here and polishes them off .
I was the one who fucked you first , ...
.. but I gave you to my baby brother because you weren 't very good .
Oh , God , no ! Um ... Claire , ...
.. let me explain ...
You absolute shit !
Explain what ? ! Explain ... what ? Listen ...
I 've been around a bit . I 've seen some creepy things in the movie business .
This is the most disgusting thing that 's ever happened to me .
- I doubt that . - What is it with you , chum ?
You can 't get it up unless little brother 's watching ?
I told you this was a bad idea .
- Really stupid . I 'm leaving . - Don 't bother .
That solves that little problem .
Jesus , Bev !
Hey !
- What 's going on ? - I don 't know , I 'm ... I 'm ... er ...
.. a bit upset .
Listen , I 'll go and catch up with her .
- I 'll tell her it was all my fault . - No !
Leave her alone .
I 'll sort it out .
I give you the winner of the 1988 Feldman Award :
Dr Elliot Mantle !
I suppose all of us know just how important it is ...
.. for a practitioner to receive the recognition of his peers .
( Elliot ) However , I feel that this award tonight ...
.. is not really for me , ...
.. but rather for those women ...
.. who have provided that most precious thing :
The gift of life .
- I want to thank Dr Angus Lawson ... - Hi , how are you ?
.. who gave me the time to pursue my own research .
But most of all I want to thank my brother , ...
.. my partner , Dr Beverly Mantle , ...
.. who , true to form , is not here wasting time basking in glory .
Here , take mine .
But is hard at work at the Mantle Clinic ...
Not true !
Not true ! I 'm here !
Oh , sorry .
I see Beverly has been doing a little basking , after all !
He has a lot to celebrate .
He has been recognised as one of North America 's leading clinicians .
Ladies and gentlemen , ...
.. Dr Beverly Mantle .
- You all right ? - Had rather a lot to drink .
Just want to say something .
- I just want to say some ... - ( microphone feedback )
I just want to say something .
( clears throat )
There 's been a fraud perpetrated here tonight .
The whole thing 's a fraud !
- He 's Beverly and I 'm Elliot ! - ( laughter )
- Just say thank you and get off . - No !
I want to say something else !
A lot of you are probably wondering ...
.. how we divide the work .
Well , it 's like this ...
I slave over the hot snatches ...
( gasps )
.. and Elliot ... makes the speeches !
For God 's sake !
I do everything for those bimbos , except take them home and stick it in them !
( audience gasps )
Well , he 's clearly been doing a lot of celebrating . Who can blame him ?
Thank you so much . Thank you .
( alarm clock beeping )
( beeping grows louder )
I 'm sorry about the catastrophe last night .
It 's true I had to smooth a few ruffled feathers this morning .
But now , baby brother , ...
.. for the good news .
Lawson has ...
.. finally offered me the associate professorship at the hospital .
- One vodka martini , Doctor . - Thank you , Sean .
- Are you going to accept ? - Of course I 'm going to accept .
It 's the next step to chairman of the department .
- What about the practice ? - It goes on as before .
- Except you 're not there . - I won 't be there as much , no .
I 'm not eating .
- Are you all right ? - Yeah , I 'm fine .
What are those ?
Dex . I 'm tired .
- Want one ? - Er ... no , thanks .
If I can fly around , teach , and do research , ...
.. surely you can find time for a few more patients ?
Sure . Why not ?
Good God !
- I didn 't know you were here . - Shh , shh . Elly 's asleep .
His plane doesn 't go till noon .
I didn 't realise you two were so friendly .
We 're not so friendly .
You gonna take a shower ?
Um ...
No , I ... er ...
You go ahead .
OK .
See ya .
It seems so ... cold and empty .
You can call it empty , or you can call it clean , sculptural .
It 's a question of the individual nervous system , I think .
That presupposes one has an individual nervous system .
Please ?
Er ... thank you , I 'll ...
I 'll think about it .
Claire ...
Yes ?
Oh , ...
.. it 's you .
Or should I say , which one of you is it ?
Please , Claire , don 't .
Are you still doing the mini-series ?
Re-shoots . The director didn 't know what he was doing .
Well , ...
.. tell me how sorry you are .
Tell me how much you miss me .
My brother and I have always shared everything .
I 'm not a thing .
I mean people , ...
.. experiences .
It 's never bothered me before now .
It 's different with me , is it ?
Yes .
Yes , it is .
Is Elliot jealous of me ?
Is he worried I 'll steal you away from him ?
No , he offered to come and talk to you for me , ...
.. to patch things up .
That would 've been amusing .
Why didn 't he ?
I wouldn 't let him .
Were you afraid I might like him as much as I like you ?
Or maybe , ...
.. when it came down to it , ...
.. l couldn 't see the difference .
No !
It doesn 't work that way between us .
I think it does .
I think you two have never come to terms ...
.. with the way it really does work between you .
( whispers ) No ! Not while he 's here .
I don 't want him to see us .
All right , ...
.. l 'll just ... separate you .
Separate us ?
What do you mean ?
( Beverly screams )
Ohh ! Ohh ! No ! No ! No ! No !
What happened ?
I 'm sorry , I 'm sorry , I was dreaming .
- What about ? - About Elliot .
- What happened ? - Oh , don 't ! Don 't !
Don 't ... touch it .
Come to bed .
Oh , Claire , ...
.. l don 't want to dream that again . I can 't !
Take one of these .
- What 's that ? - Seconal .
I guarantee you , you won 't dream .
Don 't let me dream that again .
The message that clearly emerges from these complex encounters ...
.. between physician and patient ...
.. is that there is not only a place in the clinic , ...
.. but a demand for a philosophy . A philosophy which mixes ...
They 'll discover they 're gonna have to .
( door buzzer )
Yeah .
Yeah . Look , David , I 've got to go . I 've got company .
All right , I 'll talk to you tomorrow . Bye .
- Dr Elliot Mantle ? - Yes .
Special order from Escort Embassy .
I 'm Mimsy ...
.. and this is my sister Coral .
Hi .
Would you like some of this ?
Sure .
Listen , so that I know which one of you is which , ...
.. l 'd like you ...
- Coral . - Coral .
.. to call me Elly ...
.. and you , Mimsy , ...
.. to call me Bev .
- Oh , shit ! - ( nurse ) Watch it .
( doctor ) She 's got it , Beverly .
- ( doctor ) A near thing . You OK ? - Yes , I 'm OK .
( doctor ) I thought you were shaky there for a second .
Beverly , it 's past nine .
You 're late . You 've gotta get up .
I need something to get me up .
You know where it is .
Claire , will you call Danuta , ...
.. tell her to cancel my first three patients .
I 'll never make it .
Can 't eat .
- What 's wrong ? - I don 't know , I can 't eat !
If you don 't know , I do .
Too many sleepers last night , that 's what .
Look who 's talking .
Maybe you ought to take a week off .
Just stop everything .
I 'm serious .
I 'll talk to Elly when he gets back .
- I couldn 't do anything before then . - Elliot is back .
He ... called here for you while you were in the shower .
You spoke to him ?
Well , I couldn 't help it , could I ?
I explained to him that you were staying here with me for a few days .
How did he react ?
Civilised .
He apologised ... for the scene in the bar ...
.. and I more or less ... accepted his apology .
Where are you going ?
Leo 's in town .
I told you about Leo ...
.. and my Georgia picture .
We 're close to a deal .
Don 't go . I want you to stay .
Beverly , ...
.. l can 't .
OK . Yeah .
Um , could you tell me which is the make-up trailer ?
- This one here ? - Who are you looking for ?
- Miss Niveau . - She expecting you ?
Yes , she is .
Fascinating stuff .
Lucky old Bev . He gets to rub up against the magic .
He seems totally uninterested .
Bev 's not into art .
You are ?
I 'm into glamour , ...
.. the art of glamour .
Well , here it is .
I was surprised you wanted to see me .
Give us a few minutes , please .
I like your brother very much , ...
.. and I thought it would be good ...
.. for you and me ... to be friends ...
.. if we can .
I think we can .
There 's something else .
I 'm going away to do another film . I 'm worried about leaving Bev alone .
Bev 's not alone .
No , you 're right , he 's not alone , ...
.. but he 's lonely , ...
.. even with me .
He 's developing a serious drug problem . Did you realise that ?
I thought you had the drug problem .
It 's an occupational hazard .
The same goes for Beverly .
You resent me tremendously , don 't you ?
You contribute ...
.. a confusing element to the Mantle brothers ' saga .
Possibly a destructive one .
It 's not personal .
I think you 're terrific .
But I just don 't have a role in the Mantle brothers ' saga .
I suppose , ...
.. if you liked us both ...
.. in the same way , ...
.. it might make things easier .
It has been known to happen .
I 'm sorry , ...
.. but I can 't .
Am I really that different from Beverly ?
You really are .
Claire , let me come to the airport .
Beverly , please , no public goodbyes .
Ten weeks is such a long time .
I 'll fly up ...
.. whenever there 's a break .
Claire , ...
.. let 's not lose each other .
Birchall , will you please explain ...
.. to my director and my wardrobe person ...
.. l am not about to do this movie dressed like a 10-dollar hooker .
Miss Niveau is not about to do this movie ...
.. dressed like a 10-dollar hooker .
Well ...
Claire , you will admit , at least , ...
.. your character thinks of herself as a kind of emotional hooker .
Oh , I do more than admit it .
I 'm the one who pointed it out to this ... wardrobe person .
But she 's so bloody literal-minded .
( woman sobs )
Wardrobe person ? She called me " wardrobe person " !
I know , I know .
( phone rings )
Hello . Niveau suite .
Hello ?
Have you examined her ... c-carefully yet ?
What ? Who is this ?
I 'm her gynaecologist .
You 're ... what ?
I 'm Claire Niveau 's gynaecologist !
Did you know that she was a trifurcate ?
I 'd have to classify that as a mutation .
What exactly is this ?
Is that you , Byron ?
Carefully lubricate the two prime fingers of your right hand ...
.. and insert them ...
.. into Claire Niveau 's vagina .
Instead of feeling one cervical head , ...
.. you will feel three .
Basically , this means ...
.. that you have been fucking a mutant !
Oh , Doctor , I 'm sorry , ...
.. l thought you were ready to see Mrs Randall .
Mrs Randall , please come and sit down . I don 't think we 've met .
Let me introduce myself . I 'm one of the Mantle twins .
The lesion , not surprisingly , ...
.. causes diffuse enlargement of the cervix ...
.. and , of course , our old friend , leucorrhoea .
Until very recently , ...
.. diagnosis tended to be done after a histological examination ...
.. of the removed organ . A case of throwing the baby out with the bath water .
I 'm sorry , Doctor , but your brother is waiting for you in your office .
I think you 'd better go see him .
Bev , what are you doing here ?
What 's wrong ?
I 've been hiding out at Claire 's .
I 've been hiding from you .
Hiding ?
What are you talking about ?
I was afraid of ...
I was af ... afraid you wouldn 't let me have her .
Oh , that 's crazy , Bev .
It is crazy because ...
.. yesterday ...
.. l found out that she was having an affair .
She 's unfaithful to me , Elly .
Bev , you mustn 't take it so seriously .
She 's a showbiz lady .
What can you expect ?
I 'm in love with her !
I have to take it seriously .
It can 't be love if it does this to you , can it ?
It can 't be love , Bev .
You 're right , Elly .
I was hiding from the wrong person .
( music ) " In The Still Of The Night " by The Five Satins
( music ) ln the still
( music ) Ofthe night
( music ) I held you
( music ) Held you tight
( music ) Cos I love
( music ) Love you so
( music ) Promise I 'll never
( music ) Let you go
( music ) - In the still ofthe night ( music ) - In the still
( music ) Ofthe night
( music ) I remember ...
Dance ?
No .
You go ahead .
Go on , Bev , dance with the girl .
( music ) Before
( music ) The light
( music ) Hold me again
( music ) With all ofyour might
( music ) ln the still ofthe night
( music ) ( backing singers ) ln the still ofthe night
( music ) So before
( music ) The light
( music ) Hold me again
( music ) With all ofyour might
( music ) ln the still ofthe night
( music ) ( backing singers ) ln the still ofthe night
- What 's the matter , Bev ? - I just can 't .
Bev , stay with us .
Stay with me .
Bev !
He collapsed .
Fuck , he 's not breathing !
Don 't touch him , he 's my brother !
Come on , Bev !
Come on !
( siren )
- ( Bev gasps ) - Bev ?
Bev !
Elly , ...
.. thank God you 're here .
( Elliot ) Oh , God !
Oh , Bev , ...
.. look at you , you 're a mess , ...
.. you 're a wreck .
You could 've had a stroke , Bev .
You 're lucky to be in one piece .
One piece .
Bev , ...
.. we can 't let anyone know about the drugs .
If that gets out , we 're finished .
How ... would they know ?
I had to fight them off to stop them taking a blood sample , ...
.. but I can 't stay here day and night .
I 've got to get you off the pills without anybody knowing .
Do you think I 'm really addicted ?
I 'll put you on a detox programme . I 'll supervise it myself .
There you go .
- Darling , tell me what 's going on . - Mother , I 'm at the end ofmy rope !
I cannot live in that house another second !
Every relationship has its ups and downs , dear .
You and Tommy ...
Bev , there 's a couple of things we 're gonna have to ...
Why are you taking that apart ?
Elly ... I can 't sleep .
If you 're asking me for a sleeper , you 're not gonna get one .
What am I gonna do , then ?
You 'll stay up .
Elly , I 'll die if I don 't sleep !
What if I take something when you go home ?
I 'm staying here .
What if I take something when you go to sleep ?
- I won 't . - How will you stay awake ?
I 'll take something !
You 'll take an up so that I don 't take a down ?
- This is crazy ! - Bev ...
Don 't worry about me . I 'm not you .
And don 't destroy that .
Ow , that really hurts .
This ?
This ... hurts ?
I don 't know exactly what it is that 's hurting ...
Mrs Bookman , this is a solid gold Mantle retractor .
Solid gold !
It 's the best there is .
This clinic 's the best there is !
I mean , ...
.. we have the technology .
- It couldn 't possibly hurt . - I-l didn 't mean to ...
When did you last have a period ?
I haven 't had one in four or five months .
And does it ... hurt ... when you have intercourse ?
Yes , it does .
( door closes outside )
Where was I ?
You ... asked me whether or not it hurt ...
- .. when I had intercourse ... - Yes .
What exactly did you have intercourse with ?
What do you mean ?
I just wondered .
I was once asked ...
.. to treat a woman ...
.. who had had ... intercourse ...
.. with a Labrador retriever .
I thought ...
.. maybe ...
You used this on Mrs Bookman ?
Yes .
Bev ... this is not for internals , remember ?
This is for surgical retraction . No wonder it hurt her !
No , no , it 's not the ...
There 's nothing the matter with the instrument ! It 's the body !
The woman 's body was all wrong !
( woman ) Yes , I think you 'll find his work quite interesting .
Why don 't you drop by later on this evening ?
Just a moment , please .
May I help you ?
I wonder if you could put me in touch with Mr Wolleck .
Perfect timing . Mr Wolleck is right over there working on a new piece .
- That 's Mr Wolleck ? He works here ? - Mm-hm . It 's part of his show .
I 'm sorry to keep you waiting .
I was wondering if you could help me with these .
( Wolleck ) Fascinating .
They 're quite beautiful .
What are they ?
They 're gynaecological instruments ...
.. for working on mutant women .
Mutant women ?
That 's a great theme for a show .
No , it 's not for a show . It 's not art .
I 'm a doctor , I need them for my work .
That 's a little out of my line .
What do you want me to do ?
Well , I need three-dimensional prototypes ...
.. in surgical steel , ...
.. cast , ...
.. hand-finished , ...
.. functioning .
And I thought maybe ...
Aren 't there large companies in this town ...
No ! No , no , no , I can 't go to them !
It 's too radical for them !
We 've always been too radical .
I mean ... I can 't !
It 's too ... It 's too complicated .
I think maybe we could ... work something out .
I 've had it with the bullshit from this office !
I 've asked you ten times to transfer my wife 's records to the Mount Sinai .
You haven 't done it . They refuse to admit her without them .
- What is going on ? - I 'm so sorry .
The doctors assured me they 'd been sent .
Bullshit ! I want those files in my hand before I leave !
Mr Glaser , I assure you I 'll do everything I can .
( knock at door )
( mumbles ) Not now .
( Danuta ) Doctor , I have to speak to you .
Not now !
Doctor , I 'm ... giving you my notice . I won 't work under these conditions .
Fine .
( surgeon ) We 're all set , Beverly .
We 'll use these .
( Beverly ) Give us the tools and we will do the job .
( nurse ) l-l 'm afraid I 'm not familiar ...
.. with these instruments , Doctor .
I 've just had them made .
They 're brand-new .
Well ... number them ...
- .. one to ten , from left to right . - ( Beverly bangs the table )
Give me the one ... that I ask for .
Give me number five .
- ( shouts ) Now , please ! - Yes ... number five .
Number five .
No ... !
Jesus Christ , Beverly !
I 've got ... I 've got to slow everything down .
I need something to slow everything down ...
( surgeon ) Let go !
- Oh , my God , she 's bleeding ! - Get a clamp , for God 's sake !
( surgeon shouts ) Get him the hell outta here !
I am more than willing to apologise for my behaviour .
I have been working too hard . I ...
I must be more realistic about ... my energy levels , and ...
.. about my ability to concentrate ...
.. for long periods of time under pressure .
I must add , however , ...
.. these accusations arise out of a lack of understanding ...
.. of the radical techniques my brother and I are known for .
And I think there 's a certain amount of professional jealousy involved ...
.. as well .
That 's fine , sir .
We always intended to ease ourselves into pure research , anyway .
No .
I don 't think that 'll be necessary . You have our cooperation .
They didn 't buy it , Bev .
I think they knew it was me .
They said we could 've killed her .
They said the woman could 've died .
They 're lying !
They 've always been jealous .
They won 't revoke our hospital privileges ...
.. as long as we don 't ever use them again .
Fuck ' em !
We always planned to ease ourselves into pure research .
I certainly always planned it . Didn 't you ?
There seems to be some problem about ...
.. surgical instruments .
About holding them as evidence of a disturbed mind .
Do you know what they 're talking about ?
I tried to tell you , Elly !
You don 't know the kind of patients we 've been getting lately .
You don 't know what 's going on out there .
The patients are getting strange .
They look all right on the outside , ...
.. but their insides , ...
.. they 're deformed .
Well , I had to deal with it somehow !
Radical technology was required !
You 're right , Bev .
Something radical is definitely required .
Right , I want you to take ... three of these now .
Take three around seven this evening , ...
.. three before you go to sleep , ...
.. and three when you wake up in the morning .
Yes , Doctor !
Can I trust you to do that , or have I got to sit here and watch you ?
I don 't know .
Can you trust me ?
Oh , God !
Don 't do this to me , Bev .
But I 'm only doing it to me , Elly .
Don 't you have a will of your own ?
Why don 't you just go on with your very own life ?
Do you remember the original Siamese twins ?
Chang and Eng .
They were joined at the chest .
Remember how they died ?
Mm .
Chang ...
.. died of a stroke ...
.. in the middle of the night .
He was always the sickly one .
He was always the one who drank too much .
When Eng woke up beside him ...
.. and found that his brother was dead , ...
.. he died of fright ...
.. right there in the bed .
Does that answer your question ?
Poor Elly .
Poor Bev .
Everything 's under control . I don 't see what the problem is .
Now the hospital 's getting complaints about your private practice .
They 've even approached me . Informally , of course .
Off the record , of course .
They asked me all about Bev : ls he a junkie ? Everything .
Of course , you didn 't tell them anything .
Of course not .
But you can 't go on insulating yourselves . They 're gonna nail you .
- They 're gonna be forcedto nail you . - The clinic 's none of their business .
Wow , it 's getting hard to tell the two of you apart .
What did you do that for ?
It 's my favourite fucking programme !
Elly , Elly , Elly , ...
.. you haven 't done anything wrong .
Look , your reputation 's separate from Bev 's .
You 've still got a career .
Cary , ...
.. my brother 's research is the basis of my career .
I need him .
Besides , ...
.. the truth is , nobody can tell us apart .
We are perceived as one person .
If Bev goes down the tubes , I go with him .
I 've got to get him back .
I think that 's too dangerous for you .
I think you 're the last person on earth who should try to do that .
You 've got to stay away from him now .
Sure , go find him some help , ...
.. but , for God 's sakes , Elliot , you 've got to cut yourself loose .
- It wouldn 't work . - Why ?
Look , don 't you get it yet ?
Whatever 's in his bloodstream goes directly into mine .
You can 't be serious .
That is an objective medical observation .
No , no !
No , it 's not true . You 're making it true , but it 's not true .
You don 't put these in your mouth , they don 't end up in your bloodstream !
Beverly and I just have to get synchronised .
Once we 're synchronised , it 'll be easy .
- ( slurred ) Hello ? - Who 's this ?
It 's Beverly .
Beverly , it 's Claire .
I 'm back .
Claire ?
Beverly , why haven 't I been able to reach you ?
Why haven 't you called me ?
( sobs )
Claire , ...
.. why did you betray me ?
What are you talking about ?
That ...
That man ...
That man in your hotel room .
( sobs )
Ohh !
My God !
Was that you who called ?
That was my secretary - Birchall .
He 's defiantly gay , ...
.. and you managed to gross him out completely .
( sobs )
Beverly , ...
.. l want you to come and see me .
Come to me right now .
( running water )
( phone rings )
Yeah ?
- Mr Virdo ? - Uh-huh .
- This is Dr Mantle . - Oh , yeah .
I know this sounds awfully silly , ...
.. but I 'm afraid I 've ... There 's been a terrible mix-up .
I 've locked myself ... into the clinic .
Um ... I was wondering ifyou 'd mind coming up and ... and letting me out .
I 'll be right there .
Dr Mantle , ...
.. Lee Virdo .
- Er ... - Just a minute , Mr Virdo .
OK . I think there 's ... something stuck there .
( Beverly unlocks safety chain )
What 's going on in there ?
You know ...
Endless renovations .
Oh , yeah .
Um ... You 'd better lock it .
Yeah , sure .
- Are you coming down ? - Yeah .
Are you all right ?
Yes , ...
.. l 'm fine .
- You don 't look so hot . - I 'm fine !
Thank you .
You 're the doctor .
( woman ) Excuse me , what are you doing ?
- They 're mine ! - They 've been sold !
I 'm taking them . He 's made another copy !
They 're mine and I 'm taking them !
They 're not yours !
Claire !
Beverly , my love , what 's wrong with you ?
I 've got to have some Seconal .
- I 'm sorry ... - I 've got to have some !
- I don 't have anything at all . - Oh !
Oh , fuck !
- ( whispers ) It 's all right . - No !
I 'll write a prescription for you .
They 'll fill it for you .
- I 've got to have them , Claire ! - Oui .
Don 't tell Elliot ... that I 'm here .
Why ?
I think he 's becoming ...
.. a drug addict .
( whispers ) I think he 's becoming ... dangerous .
Are you sure he didn 't call ?
( Claire ) I 'm sure .
It 's not like Elliot .
It 's been ...
It 's been almost a week .
You know Elliot . I would 've expected him to be kicking the door in by now .
Well , I haven 't heard a word from him .
Didn 't call when I was asleep ?
No .
Tell me about ...
.. these ...
.. these tools .
Tools ?
Surgical ... instruments .
You had them with you when you came .
Did I ?
Yes .
What are they for ?
They 're for separating Siamese twins .
I must go back .
Don 't go back . Stay here .
I must go now . I 'll take these .
I 'll come back .
Your brother won 't let you come back .
( Claire cries )
How could he stop me ?
( running water )
( turns offtaps )
( mock American accent ) Hey ... welcome home , kid .
We 've got to take a shot of Dilantin tonight ...
.. otherwise we might convulse .
Right .
Don 't forget .
Then we go to Percodan in the morning .
Mm , right .
Then , in the afternoon , we have a little treat .
Dilaudid . Just because it 's Saturday .
So on Monday , we kick , right ?
We agreed .
We have to start to pull things back together then .
Oh , yes , ...
.. on Monday we definitely kick .
How about some cake ?
I could go for that .
And some orange pop .
Some ice cream .
We haven 't got any ice cream , Elly .
- Mummy forgot to buy it . - ( Elliot coughs )
I want ...
.. some ice cream !
Happy birthday , Elly .
It 's not our birthday , Bev .
Yes , it is .
Happy birthday , baby brother .
We are about to separate the Siamese twins .
Don 't forget the good part !
Oh , yes !
Chang was always most concerned about dulling the pain .
Don 't waste it .
Tell me when it takes effect .
I don 't think I 'll notice anything .
You can start when you like .
Do you think ...
.. the morticulator is required , Eng ?
I think ...
.. everything is required , Chang .
Why are you crying ?
Separation can be ...
.. a terrifying thing .
Don 't worry , baby brother , ...
.. we 'll always ...
We 'll always be together .
Elly ?
I had a terrible dream .
Elly ...
Elly ?
Elly !
Elly ... Elly ... Elly ...
Elly ... Elly ...
Elly ...
.. Elly ...
( Claire ) Hello ?
Hello ?
Who is this ?
Subtitles by Visiontext